Matthew Paul

Senior - Staff Product Designer

Summary

Product Designer and Design Engineer specializing in designer, developer, and collaboration tools.

I have more than 12 years of experience designing $0 \rightarrow 1$ products, shipping software at scale, and building and maintaining design systems.

Contact

matthewcpaul.com mclydep@gmail.com (612) 865-5022 1703 Julian St #1, Denver, CO 80204

Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design University of Minnesota, Duluth, 2013

Skills

Product design

Design engineering

Design systems

Visual design

Interaction design

User experience design

Prototyping

UX research

Design vision

Product strategy

Business strategy

Systems thinking

Cross-functional collaboration

Planning and prioritization

Customer experience

Content management

Mentoring

Leadership

Visual communication

Communication skills

Growth mindset

Web development

Web standards

Accessibility

HTML

CSS

JavaScript/Typescript

React

Next.js

Work Experience

Lead Product Designer

Bubble

Sep 2023 - Jul 2024

- Led product design and UX research for a $0 \rightarrow 1$ product called Native Mobile Apps
- · Planned and prioritized every quarter of work in collaboration with the PM
- Ran usability testing sessions, synthesized feedback from private Beta users, and iterated on features until the Public Beta release
- · Led senior product designers across multiple other Editor product teams
- · Leading contributor of designing and building Bubble's new design system

Staff Product Designer

The.com

Mar 2022 - Feb 2023

- Led product, design, UX research, and design systems for this 14 person startup, building a no-code, spreadsheet-based website builder and CMS tool
- Learned from early customers through generative and evaluative research
- · Iterated and improved on their core product
- Led product design on a $0 \rightarrow 1$ product surface area called Page Generation
- · Designed and helped build a design system from scratch, in both Figma and React

Founding Product Designer

QA Wolf

Jun 2020 – Jun 2021

- · Led product, design, and UX research for this pre-seed startup
- Designed a 0 → 1 SaaS web platform for QA engineers and software development teams to automate their end-to-end browser testing
- Helped hire their first growth/sales employee, designed the documentation website, and helped develop their pricing structure & payment model

Senior Product Designer

InVision

Jun 2018 - Mar 2020

- · Redesigned the entire Inspect UI, Selection Mechanics, and Asset Manager
- Led the design of a $0 \rightarrow 1$ tool called Inspect Motion—a new developer tool that had never existed before
- · Led a design sprint with Atlassian to improve our Jira integration with InVision Studio
- · Designed and re-factored large portions of InVision's new design system

Senior Product Designer

IBM

Nov 2016 - May 2018

- Led product design of IBM Toolbelt—an application for team leaders and financial
 analysts across the company to procure and pay for tools like Slack Enterprise, GitHub
 Enterprise, Mural, a suite of DevOps tools, and more
- Collaborated with Slack, helping them research, prototype, and pitch early Slack Enterprise concepts to their C-suite executive team
- · Designed new user input models and interactions for the Watson Al chatbot

Prototyper

Apple

Jun 2016 - Oct 2016

- · Visual and interaction designer on the Apple at Work team
- · Prototyped new ideas for team communication within the iOS ecosystem
- Designed industry-specific iPhone and iPad apps for industries such as airlines, healthcare, and education

Product Designer

IBM

Jan 2014 - May 2016

- Product designer on the Enterprise Content Management team
- Responsible for UX research, visual and interaction design, and partnering with the engineering team to ship IBM's first Enterprise File Sync & Share iOS application